[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hello. Hi, I'm really excited
大家好 很高兴
to be here to talk to you today
今天能与你们分享的是
about The Qualities of Great
优秀设计的品质
My name is Lauren Strehlow, and
我叫 Lauren Strehlow
I'm a design evangelist here at
是就职于 Apple 的
Apple.
一名设计推广师
The evangelism team, our number
作为推广团队
one goal is to help developers
我们的首要目标是帮助开发者们
just like you create great apps.
创造出更好的 App
And a big part of my job is
我工作的主要内容是与
actually to work with the design
此次大会的设计师演讲者合作
presenters who are putting on
正是他们提供了
all of the awesome design
所有精心准备的
session content that you see
设计主题会议内容
here at the conference.
正如你们看到的那样
So when I started to work with
可是今年我在和这些
potential presenters this year
候选演讲者的合作过程中
about their talks, this theme of
一直会谈到
quality kept coming up, but
设计品质这一主题
nobody was talking about it head
没有人愿意正面演讲这一主题
on, so I decided to.
所以我决定要来做这件事
But I went about it a little bit
但我的方式稍微有点不同
I decided to talk to great
我决定去访问一些
designers from our developer
开发者社区中优秀的设计师们
community, such as the creative
比如 The Game Band 的
director at The Game Band.
创意总监
I also talked to the cofounders
我还与 Layers Conference 的创始人
of the Layers Conference, which
进行了会谈
is actually happening right now
就是正在对街举办的
across the street.
Layers Conference
And I talked to the VP of Design
此外我也访问了可汗学院的
at Khan Academy.
设计副总裁
I also talked to some of my
当然 我也与许多
great colleagues here at Apple
优秀的 Apple 设计师同事畅谈过
who work in a wide variety of
他们有着不同的设计原则
They work in type design, sound
他们设计的内容包括文字
design, motion, visual, and
音效 动作 视觉
interaction design.
以及交互等
These are all real people who I
他们非常棒
truly admire and respect, and I
我非常钦佩他们
think they have created great
因为他们创造了很棒的 App 和游戏
tremendous caliber.
有着广泛的受众
So I conducted a series of
所以我进行了一系列采访
I talked to 13 people, and I
我一共采访了 13 个人
asked them a ton of questions to
问了许多问题
discover what quality means to
试图发掘对他们而言 品质是什么
them, what challenges they face,
他们所面对的挑战有哪些
and what they do to strive for
以及他们为了追求卓越设计
excellence in design.
做了些什么
So before you think any of this
你们可能怀疑
is scripted, I actually didn't
采访都是事先安排好的
give anybody these questions in
但我没有提前向任何人
advance.
透露问题
So everything you're about to
所以你们今天
hear today is real reactions to
听到的 是对这些问题的
these questions.
真实回答
I collected over 15 hours of
我收集了超过 15 个小时的
interview footage, and I've
采访资料
distilled it down to the very
然后编辑并保留下了
essence of these responses.
答案中的关键部分
So the audio clips you're about
所以你们今天将会听到的音频片段
discovered about quality in
是我对高品质设计
great design.
要求的总结
So today, we're going to dig
今天我们将会
into interpretations of quality
深入地探讨对品质的理解
and how it influences our
以及它是如何影响
perceptions and design
我们的观念以及设计方向的
We're also going to talk about
我们也将讨论
its effect on people's lives.
它对人们生活的影响
[laughs] Actually, this is
[ 笑声 ] 事实上
really exciting because it
这个过程很让人兴奋
turned out to be so much more
因为这比我预想的
than what I expected.
要复杂得多
We're also going to hear about
我们将会听到
aspirations from the designers
受访设计者的
that I interviewed, to hear what
远大抱负 了解是什么
drives them, what goals they
驱动他们前行
have when they're striving for
以及他们追求高品质时
quality, even if those goals
有哪些目标
seem unattainable.
即使目标遥不可及
And finally, I want to share
最后 我将会分享一些
some techniques that were
我在采访过程中
revealed while asking people
发现的一些常用技术
And I hope that these techniques
我希望这些技术
can help you approach the
能在你们为广大用户
challenge of designing for a lot
设计产品时
of people.
起到一定帮助
So this session is all about the
所以这场会议的内容就是
qualities of great design
设计师们对优秀设计的
defined by designers.
品质定义
So let's kick things off, and
现在让我们开始吧
get started, and hear a few
首先听听大家
answers to this one simple
对一个简单问题的回答
question: What is quality?
“什么是品质”
&gt;&gt; Quality is nothing else than
品质其实就是
what we agree upon is good.
我们认为好的东西
&gt;&gt; If something is quality, it
如果某件事物是高品质的
implies that there is nothing
说明它不是被
random about it.
随意制作出来的
&gt;&gt; The number one thing is just
最重要的是人们
that something with a lot of
付出了大量的
care and time went into it.
关心与时间
&gt;&gt; It's one of those things that
这是人们能够
people can feel it when they
感受到的
feel it, and it's very hard for
但人们往往不能
them to put their finger on it.
真正触摸到
&gt;&gt; All right.
是的
This one I can really relate to.
我深有体会
I'm totally a feeler, and so
我自己就以感受见长
this naturally led me to ask a
所以我很自然问出
follow-on question: What does
下一个问题 “高品质是什么感受呢？”
&gt;&gt; Does it feel like somebody
它会让人们感觉到有人
has thought of you already and
已经为他们考虑一切
all the things that you need are
所有的需求都能轻易
easy to get to and very
得到满足 并且容易理解
&gt;&gt; I think that when I'm
就我自己而言
thinking about things that are
当我想到高品质的事物
quality or handling things that
或者处理高品质的事物时
are quality, it's things that
我认为它在操作时
aren't painful to use in any
不会让我有任何不适
way, which could be, like,
这些不适可以包括
mentally painful, physically
心理上 生理上
painful, emotionally painful,
以及情绪上的
things that don't make me feel
高品质的事物不会让我感到
uncomfortable, or dumb, or
不舒服 不好用
[laughs] or inconvenienced.
[ 笑声 ]或者不方便
&gt;&gt; If you just launch the app
如果你打开了一个 App
and you feel, as you use it, oh,
在使用过程中
well, this feels like
感到你正在使用的技术
I'm using.
是艺术级的
This feels like it's easier for
感到这个 App 可以
me to get things done.
让我更轻松地完成任务
I feel more productive.
我变得更高效了
I feel like I'm able to achieve
感觉自己能够得到更好的结果
&gt;&gt; All the concentration that
你能够专注于
you're building up goes to the
你手头上的事情 也就是
actually want to do.
你真正想做的事情
And that to me feels like
对我来说 这就是高品质
quality.
如果你能做到以上这些
and people can be very creative,
人们会因为你的设计而更具创造力
and make beautiful things, or
能创造更多美好的事情
have special moments through a
或者能通过某个设备获得特殊的经历
device -- for example, by taking
比如说可以拍出很多很棒的照片
really good pictures, or sharing
可以与朋友
pictures with friends, or
分享照片
finding the right music to play
可以在对的时间播放
at the right moment, or, you
对的音乐
know, doing fun stuff with
可以使用 Facetime
FaceTime, and seeing people on
做有趣的事情
the other side of the world that
与世界另一端
you haven't seen in a long time
好久不见的朋友相见
-- all of that is very special.
这些都是很特别的事情
And again, none of that is
而且 这些东西跟你的 UI 无关
None of that is about what
也跟你选择的交互方式
stuff.
无关
That should all be obvious, and
品质是一种无需言明
completely in the background.
隐藏于背景的东西
&gt;&gt; Wow. I just love that, that
我很爱这一点
quality isn't about the UI or
品质与 UI 无关
interactions, that it's about
与交互无关
the moment, the people.
只是关于当下的时刻以及人们
You know, these are the people
你要知道 这些人们将会是你
that you're designing for, and
设计的用户
you're helping them create
你要帮助他们创造
memories and share those moments
并分享美好的
with others.
回忆瞬间
That is what this is all about.
这就是重点所在
So how do you design for that?
那么要如何设计做到这一点呢?
Well, I actually asked that
老实说 我真的问了这个问题
&gt;&gt; It's hard.
这个问题是挺难的
&gt;&gt; [laughter] Yeah.
[ 笑声 ] 是的
I hope you weren't actually
希望你们不要真的
hoping for a real answer here.
认为会有一个标准的答案
It's definitely very hard, and
这是个很难的问题
we have 55 minutes to dig into
我们还有 55 分钟可以来深入讨论
So we just heard a ton of
刚刚我们听到了有关
answers to this question, what
什么是品质的众多回答
We heard that it is what we
它是人们公认是
agree upon is good, that it's
好的东西
not random, it's something that
不是随意堆砌
shows a lot of care and time
而是能够体现人们的付出
went into it, and it feels like
让人们感觉到
somebody has thought of you
有人为他们想到了一切
It can also be not painful in
它不会让人不适
any way, and it feels state of
还很有艺术感
Quality things make it easier to
高品质的事物能让
get things done.
完成事情变得更轻松
And finally, your concentration
你的注意力
goes to the thing that you
也会集中于你
really want to do, like sharing
真正想做的事情
that picture or playing your
比如分享照片或者
favorite song.
播放你最爱的歌曲
So by asking about quality, it
什么是高品质这一问题
resulted in many different
有着许多不同的回答
answers, but what's so great
但是它们正好
about that is that it reflects
反映出了每个人
truly care about.
真正关心的东西
And of course, people care about
当然 每个人的
different things, so it makes
关注点不同
complete sense that they all
因此人们对不同 App 和游戏的品质
of what quality is when it
有不同的理解
applies to apps and games.
也是很正常的
So we have a lot to get to
今天我们要讨论的很多
today, but I really want to dig
但我想深入探讨
into just a couple of these
几个回答
I think they're all great, but
这些回答都很好
let's just dig into this first
我们首先讨论这一个
And we're going to listen to the
接下来 我将会
clip one more time.
再播放一次刚刚的音频
&gt;&gt; If something is quality, it
如果一件事物是高品质的
implies that there is nothing
就意味着它不是
random about it.
随机形成的
&gt;&gt; During this interview with
在采访过程中
Nicole, she explained that not
Nicole 解释道
random to her meant not slapped
对她而言 不是随机的是指不是拼凑而成的
And she used this word
她还用了另外一个词 “深思熟虑的”
Great designs are considered.
好的设计都是经过深思熟虑的
They're organized, and they show
它们是有组织的 并能够
a thought process has taken
体现出确实是经过思考的
And what I found really
在交流中
interesting is that she said
还有一点很有意思
that that's really visible to
就是她认为品质是可见的
people, that that visibility of
而有关设计品质
quality in design actually came
可见性的问题
up in another interview when I
在另一个采访中也被提及
was talking with Mike.
在我采访 Mike 的时候
&gt;&gt; I guess this is probably a
我想这可能有点
little cliché sounding, but
老生常谈
it's often the little things
但往往是细微之处
that are the telltale signs
才是体现
about craftsmanship.
工艺之处
&gt;&gt; Okay, we have to pause right
好的 先暂停一下
there because we're about to
因为我们不想在设计会议上
talk about craft in a design
讨论工艺部分
session, and Mike already called
而 Mike 也说了
it out that it's a little
这部分有些老生常谈
cliché, but before we listen to
但在我们开始听
the rest of this clip, I need
接下来的音频前
you to imagine that you're in
我希望你们可以想象现在
the audio booth with us.
正和我们待在录音棚中
There's not going to be anything
屏幕上不会显示任何字
on screen, so I want you to
我希望你们可以
really focus on the words that
专心于 Mike 接下来
Mike is about to say.
说的每个字
Okay, here we go.
好了 让我们开始吧
&gt;&gt; We're sitting in this room
我们坐在这个房间里
here, and there's these panels
墙上有很多控制面板
on the wall, and the panels have
这些面板之间
a little bit of a gap between
之间有一些间隙
them.
当我们从上到下
the gap as you look from the top
扫视这面墙的时候
of the wall to the bottom of the
可以看到间隙的宽度
And if there's variable
如果这些间隙的
separation or variable width of
宽度不一致
that gap, you just get the sense
我们会觉得
that it wasn't well crafted.
工艺不好
&gt;&gt; Right. So really, while Mike
没错 所以当 Mike
was talking about those variable
在录音棚中讨论
widths in the gaps of the panels
控制面板之间的间隙时
in the audio booth, you know, I
我知道
understood that he's saying that
他其实在说
those details are visible, and
细节是可见的
they matter a lot.
并且至关重要
And it's through consideration
而只有通过仔细斟酌
and being really deliberate, and
以及深思熟虑
thinking through every single
考虑到每个具体的细节
detail thoughtfully, well, that
才能展示出品质
And so being really into your
所以 你需要
craft here is the point because
专注于工艺
the best things that we love are
人们喜欢的东西
not random.
不是随机形成的
They're not slapped together.
你的作品并不是随意堆砌
They're intentional through
而是经过了对细节的推敲
And if you can do that, that's
如果你能做到这些 那就是品质
So let's explore one more answer
接下来 让我们研究
to the question, what is
关于什么是品质
quality, and listen to the clip
的另一个回答 再听一遍录音
&gt;&gt; The number one thing is just
最重要的是
that something with a lot of
人们付出了大量的
care and time went into it.
关心与时间
&gt;&gt; This one in particular really
我对这一回答
resonated with me because when
很有共鸣
you're writing questions to
因为在为采访撰写问题时
interviews like, what is
比如 “什么是品质？”
quality, you naturally end up
你自然地会先问自己
asking yourself, and to me,
而对我而言
quality is all about care.
品质就是关心
So when I heard care connected
而将关心与品质相联系的
to quality not only from that
不仅仅是刚才
clip we just heard from Travis,
音频中的 Travis
but it also came up in my
我在与 Gary 的对话中
interview with Gary.
他也谈到了这一点
&gt;&gt; If it's quality, it's better
高品质的东西
than something that's not
比起其他产品好
quality by virtue of someone
是因为有
caring about it.
设计者的关心
&gt;&gt; Right. I totally agree that
没错 关心确实能让
caring makes things better.
事情变得更好
For example, I care about this
举个例子 我十分重视这次
presentation, so, naturally,
演讲所以 自然地
it's just a little bit better
它会比我根本
than if I didn't care about it
不在意它来的要好一些
So now, I feel like we should
那么现在 我觉得我们应该
dig into, what is care?
讨论一下 关心是什么
Okay, we're going to stick with
好的 接下来我们将会继续
a few interview clips from Gary
播放一些采访 Gary 的音频
so you can hear more of the full
你们也可以听到 更多完整的对话
So I asked him, "How would you
我问他 “那你怎样
describe care?"
描述关心呢“
&gt;&gt; Just that someone, excuse my
就是有的人 通俗一点说
French, gave a [beep].
在乎这件事
&gt;&gt; [laughter] I'm not sure if
[ 笑声 ] 我不确定这是不是
that's a WWDC first, but it's
WWDC 上的首例
simple.
但是直截了当 我很喜欢
[laughs] Really, what he's
[ 笑声 ] 真的 他的意思是
saying here is that care is a
关心就是动力
So how do you look at care in
那你是怎么看待设计中的
design?
关心呢
&gt;&gt; I look at it from 2 lenses of
我会从两个角度来看待
care.
我是否给予了它足够的关心
best it could be?
把它做到最好
But do I also care about what
我是否同样关心了
your experience is?
用户体验
Be it you.
不管这个用户是你
Be it my mum.
还是我妈妈
Be it my next-door neighbor.
还是我的邻居
Be it anybody around the world.
还是世界上任何一个人
You have to kind of, sort of
你需要尽量
take yourself out of the
减少主观看法
equation, put yourself in their
尝试去从
shoes so you can be sure that
用户角度考虑
their experience is a quality
这样才能确保 他们能享受高品质的使用体验
So you have to care enough to do
你需要足够关心才能做到
It's not just about caring about
这不仅仅是关心你自己的感受
your own sense of, "Oh, I like
“我超爱我的设计
my design, and I cared enough to
我会足够关心它
make it good for me."
让它变成我喜欢的样子”
It's about it being good for as
而是要让它
many people as possible or for
让尽可能多的人感到舒服
the target audience, if it
如果产品的受众较小
happens to be a more narrowly
则需要满足目标群体的需求
&gt;&gt; Right. So when I heard this,
所以当我听到他这么说时
I was just, I wanted to know
我立刻就想知道要
how, immediately.
怎么去做
How do you design that
怎样能针对用户体验
experience for others, and how
设计产品
do you know when you've made
又如何才能知道是否有进展呢
&gt;&gt; I think sometimes we look at
有时候 当我们面对着
a tangled mess of problems that
一堆亟需解决的问题时
we need to solve, and if, at the
如果我们可以
end, you can look at the result
看到结果后再继续
and go, that is so much better,
那应该会更简单
and if it came easy, it wouldn't
但如果成果来得太轻易
be as fun, but the fact that you
又没有那么有趣了
sweated over it, that you really
如果你辛苦付出
worked hard at it, that it gave
努力工作
you sleepless nights, that you
失过眠
poured late nights and weekends
在深夜和周末加班
into solving those problems,
来解决这些问题
combined effort, team effort,
再加上大家共同努力 团队协作
the end result is so much more
最终结果才会更让人满足
I love it when we work hard and
与随手可得的创意相比
get there more than when ideas
我更喜欢那些需要付出
just come easily.
心血的成果
I worry that we've actually
我担心如果我们没有足够努力
missed something by not working
那我们可能会错过一些东西
hard.
如果结果来的太容易
complacent, and I don't think
我们就会容易自满
you get anywhere rewarding
我不认为什么事情是可以
without doing hard work.
不劳而获的
&gt;&gt; I really understood this
当 Gary 将努力付出与
point about working hard after
山地自行车对比起来解释时
Gary related this to mountain
我完全理解了他的意思
We talked about this for a
我们就这一点讨论了一会儿
while, so I'm just going to
为了方便你们理解
summarize that conversation here
我将对话进行了总结
Essentially, you have to work
对话的重点在于
really hard to get to the top of
只有竭尽全力到达山顶
the mountain, and then you can
才能享受
have a ton of fun on the
下山时成倍的愉悦
Now, it's not as much fun if you
如果你一开始就在山顶上
just started at the top and went
那下山时就没那么有趣
down because it's really all of
因为正是你的时间 精力 辛苦
that brings you to the top of
把你带到了山顶
the mountain that makes the view
让一路的景象
all that more beautiful and
更加美丽
makes the ride down so much more
也让下山的旅程更加有趣
fun.
在生活中 关心自然意味着付出
more time and effort because you
更多的时间与精力
have a passion to achieve your
因为你对目标十分热枕
goals, and you'll do whatever is
愿意为了实现
needed to meet your own
期望而付出任何努力
And yeah, that's totally a lot
没错 这确实需要付出
of work, but that hard work has
但辛勤的付出都会有
a payoff, and it's really
令人满意的回报
And the payoff, well, that's why
而这个回报
you did it in the first place,
也是你做这件事情的起因 不是吗
You have a goal, and you make it
你设定了一个目标 然后你实现了它
That's just awesome.
简直不能再棒了
So quality is all about care,
总的来说 品质与关心密切相关
and because you care, you're
正是因为你关心
going to put in that time and
所以你愿意付出时间与
effort to make things great.
精力来将它做好
And that's just one answer to
这是人们对
the question, what is quality?
“什么是品质”的另一回答
And because there are so many
人们对品质有着许多
different interpretations of
不同的理解
quality, well, that means it's
这样意味着
just really hard to achieve.
高品质很难实现
A little bit later, we're going
稍后 我们将会讨论
to get into some techniques to
一些技巧
hopefully help make the process
希望可以让
of designing a little bit
设计的过程
easier.
容易一些
But for now, let's just recap
但是现在 让我们来
what we've learned.
复习刚刚所学的内容
So far, just by asking a few
通过一些简单的问题
simple questions, we've learned
我们了解到
that quality means something
不同人对品质
different to different people,
有着不同理解
that it's not random -- it is
并且不是随意形成的
crafted and considered.
是经过认真雕琢和仔细考虑的
Quality is the result of time,
品质是时间 精力
effort, and care.
以及关心的结果
And it is just hard to achieve,
要做到确实很难
but that's okay.
但没关系
Quality has many different
对品质有着许多不同版本的理解
What is yours?
那你的理解是什么呢
I think this is really important
我认为很有必要
to ask yourself, what is
问自己这个问题
quality, and what does it mean
什么是品质 品质对你意味着什么
to you, and what does it mean to
对你的 App 或者
your app or game, because that's
游戏意味着什么
going to reveal what you truly
因为这些问题能帮助你了解
care about, and that's going to
你自身真正关心的是什么
help you focus on what you're
也能帮助你更专注于
working towards going forward.
你将要做的事情
So let's just pause here for a
让我们先暂停一下
moment, and we actually need to
我们需要稍微
go back a bit.
回顾一下
Why does quality matter in the
首先 品质到底有什么意义
Why are we even talking about it
为什么我们要在 WWDC 上
here at WWDC?
讨论这个问题呢
Well, what's the significance?
意义是什么呢
Let's just ask, why is quality
让我们换个方式问 为什么品质很重要
&gt;&gt; Quality impacts the world
品质每天会从许多方面
that we interact with in so many
无时无刻地
different ways all the time
影响我们的
throughout our day.
日常生活
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Travis is totally
没错 Travis 说的很对
Throughout our day, there are
我们每一天
things that we eat, drink, wear,
吃的 喝的 穿的
I mean, even the air we breathe.
甚至是所呼吸的空气
They all have some level of
它们的品质
quality that impacts us.
都在影响我们
And we expect quality in our
而在我们也期待高品质的
friendships, in our family, in
朋友关系 家庭关系
our relationships.
和恋人关系
We seek out people who show us
我们更喜欢那些尊重我们
respect, who care about us and
在乎我们 让我们感觉很好的人
I mean, nobody keeps around
我的意思是 没人会喜欢
poor-quality friends.
带来负能量的朋友
We also expect quality from the
我们对日常使用的产品
products that we use and the
及事物也有着
things that we use every day.
品质的要求
We expect them not to break.
我们不希望它们坏掉
And if they do break, well, we
如果它们坏了 我们会觉得
tend to think that they're cheap
它们很廉价
and not well made, and we
做工不好
typically won't buy them again.
并且通常不会选择回购
So yeah, the concept of quality
所以 品质这一理念
impacts our every day, and it's
影响着我们每天的生活而
really in everything.
它确实存在于所有事情之中
While it's really wide reaching
虽然品质听起来似乎
and broad, there seems to be
很宽泛
something so special about
但一些特质
quality, but what is it?
这些特质是什么呢
What makes quality special?
是什么让品质如此特殊呢
&gt;&gt; They say, like, oh, I cooked
人们有时候会说 这是我用爱煮的东西
this with love, and it can just
虽然可能煮的只是鸡蛋
be eggs or whatever, but it does
但是它的味道
taste different, and I think
又确实不同
Jessie and I like to think that
我想 Jessie 和我都认为
whatever we do, that sort of
不管我们做什么
love for what we're doing comes
我们对事物的爱都
through.
贯穿其中
&gt;&gt; Right? I know these two
对吧 这两位女士
ladies absolutely love what they
是真的热爱她们的事业
do, and I know I can feel it
当我遇到了真正热爱的人时
when someone really loves
我也能感受到
And to Elaine's first point, you
而 Elaine 所说的第一点
know, I think everyone here
我相信大家都会有同感
knows that Mom and Dad's food
爸爸妈妈做的饭菜
just tastes a little bit better
总是要好吃一些
because it's made with that care
因为里面有关心与爱
So what really Elaine means by
Elaine 所正在表达的是
this is your intentions are
你的想法是能够被感知的
So if your intention is to
也就是说 如果你的目的在于
create something great and you
创造一些优秀的东西
do everything you need to do to
你也尽你所能的去
achieve that, people are going
实现它 人们会知道
to know.
你的付出
They're going to feel it.
他们也能够感受到
And the reverse is true too.
反之亦然
You know, if you rushed and you
当你为了赶进度
didn't really care about the
而不关心你 App UI 中
look of settings in your app UI,
设置的外观
well, it's going to impact the
那它将会影响
overall feeling that people have
人们对你的 App 的
about your app.
整体印象
So throughout the course of
在我进行这些采访的过程中
conducting these interviews, I
“品质” 这一词几乎
"quality" everywhere, like
无处不在 比如高品质咖啡
quality coffee or quality meats.
高品质肉类
And even one night when I was
甚至有一天晚上我
working really late, and I
加班到深夜时
ordered a pizza, and the pizza
点了个披萨外卖
box said, "Our commitment is
上面写着 “我们专注于品质”
[laughs] So I see the word
[ 笑声 ] 所以这个词
everywhere now.
已经无处不在了
It's really pervasive, from
它渗透在生活的方方面面
signs to badges, to labels.
从标语到徽章再到标签
So I brought this up in a few of
所以我在一些采访中
the interviews, not because I
也提及了这一问题
wanted to know what people
并不是想知道人们对
thought of labeling, but,
标签的看法是什么
instead, to ask, why do we tend
而是想了解为什么我们
to be drawn towards things that
更喜欢有品质
are quality?
的东西
&gt;&gt; Well, survival instinct at
幸存者本能就是一切的根源
On a more deep level, I guess,
我认为更深层次的问题是
why do we desire quality?
为什么我们渴望品质
We desire quality because we
我们渴望品质是因为
want to live.
我们想要生存
And a good survival strategy for
一个优秀生存战略就是
living is to put things into our
将东西放到我们自己身上
body, to eat things, or to wear
像吃东西
things, or to drive in things,
穿衣服 开好车
or to live in things that are
或者居住在安全的
safe and have been well
精心建造的建筑中
constructed so they aren't going
只有这样
to cause us bodily harm.
我们才不会发生身体损伤
And so I think purely on a
从简单的生存层面看来
survival level, quality is a
品质对我们来说
very important concept for us.
是一个非常重要的概念
It's a very important attribute
我们所追求的事物都
that we seek in everything.
需要有品质这一重要特质
&gt;&gt; Mike explained a bit further
在这次采访中 Mike
during this interview.
做出了更进一步的解释
We were talking about this
我们对一个
fictitious butcher shop, and if
虚构的肉店进行了讨论
we were in this shop, quality
假设我们身在这个肉店里
would be communicated not only
那不仅是商品本身
by the products itself, but also
体现出品质
the shop being really clean and
商店的整洁干净以及
interacting with the really nice
店员之间的友好沟通
people that work there.
都体现出品质
Every facet of the entire
整个体验的每一方面
experience would meet your
都能满足你的期望
expectations, [laughs] and it
[ 笑声 ] 那它就会和
would also be connected to that
品质
proposition of quality.
联系起来
And that evokes trust.
高品质会带来信任
Trust comes from products
对产品的信任来自于
upholding their promise, and
产品能够信守承诺
that quality experience is far
高品质的体验
more important than any label
比起任何标签都重要的多
because I am definitely not
我不建议你
suggesting that you add a label
给你的 App 加上
to your apps because you
高品质的标签
[laughs] definitely don't need
[ 大笑 ] 因为不需要
Every facet of your app
你 App 的每个细节
experience, from the screenshots
从 App Store 上的
on the App Store to the
屏幕快照 到描述
description, to how you respond
再到你对用户评论的回复
to your app's interface, these
再到 App 界面
experiences, these interactions
所有的体验和交互
that you have with people, that
对用户来说
communicates the quality about
正是你的 App 或者游戏
your app or your game.
品质的体现
And you don't want a label
所以你根本就不需要什么标签
Why?
为什么呢
&gt;&gt; In a way, it's like saying
从某种程度上说 这就像在说
you're cool.
你很酷
Like, being cool doesn't involve
但说出来
saying you're cool.
就不酷了
[laughs] And, you know, you only
[ 笑声 ] 你们也知道
say that someone else is cool.
我们只会说别人很酷
It's only something which can be
从某种程度上说
sort of determined by an outside
这是要由别人来
party, in a way.
评判的
And even then, there's a certain
虽然有些时候
context where it feels more
也不一定需要
appropriate than others.
别人评判
Like, if we're talking about
例如当我们谈论
Thelonious Monk and we're just
Thelonious Monk 时
talking about jazz in the '50's,
当我们讨论 50 年代的爵士音乐时
like, that's cool.
我们很酷
That's the birth of cool, right.
就是很酷
[laughs] That's where it's,
[ 笑声 ] 这种情况下
like, totally appropriate to use
完全可以使用
that kind of term, but that's an
酷这类词
earned coolness.
这是自己挣来的
And so quality has to be earned.
同样品质也要自己争取
&gt;&gt; I think Mike makes a really
我觉得 Mike 说的很有道理
So the significance of quality
所以品质的重要性显而易见
As we heard, it impacts our
正如我们听到的
every day, it can be felt, and
品质影响我们的日常生活 能被感知
it evokes trust in the people
也能激发你 App
that are using your app.
用户的信任
All right.
好的
Now, everyone I talked to
每个我在采访中
throughout these interviews,
接触的人
they all have a passion for
都展示出对卓越的追求
excellence, so we're going to
所以接下来我们将
talk about four design
讨论四种设计倾向
aspirations, and these four
这四种设计倾向
aspirations really stood out to
对我来说十分特别
me because, well, they seemed
因为它们看起来
just so incredibly elusive and
别具一格
hard to achieve.
又难以实现
But these designers use them as
但是这些设计师们还是将
motivation to strive for quality
它们当作追求品质的动力
in their work, and these
这些倾向
aspirations are to design things
是为了设计一些
that are simple, stunning,
简单 出色
timeless, and leave a positive
永不过时且能给人们
impact on people's lives.
生活带来积极影响的事物
So we're going to dig into each
我们将会深入的挖掘
one of these to discover why
这四种设计倾向
they're important and also how
研究它们为什么这么重要
they provide motivation to
以及它们是如何为优秀设计
create great design.
提供动力的
All right.
好的
Let's start with simplicity.
让我们从简单开始讨论
This came up in response to this
它来自于采访中对
question: What makes a great
“什么是好的 App ” 这一问题的回答
&gt;&gt; It's simple.
它要很简单
It doesn't try to do more than
不试图作出超越
it needs to do.
需求的事情
And what it does, it does it
它只会将要做的事情做好
&gt;&gt; I don't know about you, but I
不知道你们有没有听说过
have heard that a lot.
但我经常听到这一说法
[laughs] So I'm sure you've
[ 笑声 ] 所以我相信你们之前
heard it before too.
肯定也有听过
But there's got to be a reason
但简单一词不断重复
why that phrase is on repeat,
肯定有它的理由的
and I was really thinking about
所以我在采访之后思考
this after the interview.
这一个问题
You know, why should apps be
为什么 App 要简单呢
simple, and why is that a good
为什么简单是件好事呢
Well, it finally clicked for me
有一天下班
one day after work.
我突然想通了
I got home, I needed to cook
我回到家
some dinner, and I needed an app
需要煮晚饭
to help me with a recipe, to not
那我就需要 App 来提供食谱
make cooking any harder than it
让煮饭不那么困难
And as soon as I was home, I
而我到家之后
remembered that I needed to go
我想起来我需要为两只狗狗
ahead and put, book pet care for
预定宠物护理
my two dogs because I'm going on
因为我在 WWDC 后要去旅游
Aw, aren't they cute?
哦 它们真可爱
[laughs] Okay, we have to stop
[ 笑声 ] 好的 就到这里
before I get distracted.
我要在分心之前继续演讲
We're talking about two tasks
我们现在有两个任务：
here, cooking dinner and pet
煮晚餐和宠物护理
Why do the apps that help me
为什么这些 App 可以帮助我
with those, why do they need to
完成任务
be simple?
为什么它们要简单呢
Well, it's because I don't go
因为我不可能
into them all the time, so they
一直盯着它们
need to be instantly
所以它们需要易于操作
understandable, as if I already
就好像我已经
know how to use them.
知道如何使用了一样
So familiar navigation and
所以熟悉的导航以及手势操作
gestures really help with that.
起到了很大作用
You know, the goal is launch the
目的在于 当我打开这个 App 时
app, I totally get it, and I can
我能够明白如何操作
get the task done.
并能完成我的任务
But why else should they be
除此之外 还有什么要做到
simple?
简单的呢
Well, it could be a good day or
这么说吧 不管每天是好是坏
a bad day, but I'm using these
我都需要在日常生活中
apps in real life, and that's
使用这些 App
where all of my mental energy
我的所有心力
should be, not wasted on a
不应该花费在令人困惑的
confusing app UI, interaction,
UI 互动或者界面上
Apps should not be a burden, and
App 不应该成为负担
it's a lot easier to get back to
只有当 App 足够简单时
real life when they're simple.
人们才能更快的回到真实生活中
So how would you describe
那又如何定义
simplicity in apps and games?
App 和游戏的简单呢
&gt;&gt; It just has to work.
只要它能用就好
&gt;&gt; Right. It just has to work
没错只要用户
for the people that are using
能够使用就好
But there's actually something
但其实还有一些条件
You don't want people to feel
你并不希望人们分心
Simple, easy-to-understand apps
简单 易懂 能工作的
that just work, well, they help
App 能帮助人们
keep people focused.
保持专注
I know for me, I can get really
就我自身而言
easily overwhelmed if
我很容易被
something's out of place.
不需要的东西影响
It can just take me out of that
它会给我一种不合时宜
experience, and that makes
的感觉 让完成
getting the task done even
任务变得更加困难
harder.
我在采访 Jessie 时 与她
about this, and I asked her,
讨论了这一问题 我问她
what does she look for in great
对优秀 App 有些什么要求
&gt;&gt; Make my life feel a little
能让我的生活变得更轻松
bit easier or make my life feel
或者能让我的生活变得
a little bit nicer or more
美好或者更丰富
&gt;&gt; I think that is just spot on.
我觉得她说的很对
Make my life feel a little bit
通过使用简单 专注
easier by being simple, focused,
易懂 但却能完美的
instantly understandable, and
完成一件事情的 App
just do one thing really, really
会让我的生活变得
well.
更轻松
That is the goal.
这就是目标所在
All right, this next aspiration
那接下来 我们要讨论的设计倾向
is to be stunning, and this came
是出色
up when I was talking to
这是 Caroline 和我对话时
Caroline.
提出的
I asked her, "What communicates
我问 Caroline “好的视觉设计
great visual design?"
是怎样体现的呢”
&gt;&gt; Just that polish.
尽善尽美
Does it look great?
它看起来好吗
Does it look stunning?
它看起来出色吗
And then, the other level of
然后针对
polish, on a different kind of
不同类型 App
app, like a game or something,
比如游戏或者其他
to me is making it feel
对我来说 尽善尽美
beautiful as an experience, like
就是给用户提供更美妙的体验
it feels like a work of art.
人们觉得它是一个艺术品
&gt;&gt; Right, yes.
就是这样
So we talked a little bit
我们就这一问题
further about this, and Caroline
进行了深入探讨
explained that what she means by
Caroline 解释到 她所说的尽善尽美是指
polish is things lining up just
所有事物都按你想要的
the way you intend them to be,
方式排列
including how it feels.
包括给人们的感觉
You know, swipe animations
正如轻扫动画
lining right up with those swipe
与这些轻扫手势是相关的
And the best apps appear
而优秀 App 的
visually perfect, and that is
视觉效果十分完美
just totally remarkable.
这也很值得称道
And she also mentioned games.
Caroline 还提到了游戏
Games should absolutely aspire
游戏更应该力求出色
Games are a perfect escape from
游戏是人们逃离现实世界进入
this world into a different one.
到另一个世界的完美方式
And they accomplish this through
它们需要通过
stunning, immersive visuals.
出色的沉浸式视觉效果来做到
I mean, I love TV and movies,
虽然电视和电影也是
but that's a really passive
很好的逃离方式 但非常被动
In games, well, they're an
而游戏能为我提供一种
active one, and that's why I
主动的逃离方式
love them.
这也是我爱它们的原因
But there is one essential thing
但有一件重要的事情
that all games must do.
所有游戏都需要做到
They must teach you, the player,
它们需要教会玩家游戏规则
the rules.
规则是人们对
impression that people have of a
大部分游戏的
lot of games, so it makes me
第一印象
really sad when games make a bad
当我对有些游戏的
first impression because when
第一印象不好时 我很难过
I'm trying to learn, well, the
因为在我学习规则时
rules feel slapped together,
它们就像是随意堆在一起
added on last minute, or it just
匆忙赶制
doesn't feel a part of the
就像不属于游戏世界一样
So I decided to ask Sam, who's
所以我决定问问 Sam
working on an upcoming game
他正在准备一个新的游戏
called Where Cards Fall, "How do
叫 Where Card Fall
you learn the rules of the game
我问他“要如何
all while staying in the game's
在沉浸游戏世界的同时学习
world?"
游戏规则呢”
&gt;&gt; With games in particular,
就游戏这一特定类别而言
there's a real joy that can come
你可以从发现人物能力
from discovering what they can
并自行探索规则中
do and learning for yourself.
获得真实的乐趣
People tend to remember things
人们倾向于记住
the best when they experience
亲身经历的事情
them themselves, when they learn
通过主动发现
them through some sort of active
来学习规则
discovery.
才能记住规则
So if we give them too much at
如果我们一开始就
the beginning, we're robbing
准备了太多东西
them of that chance to reward
我们就剥夺了玩家们获得
their own curiosity.
好奇心奖励的权利
So we always want to make sure
所以我们一直都努力地让
that they stay curious, that
玩家们保持好奇心
they stay interested throughout
让他们在整个游戏过程中
the entire experience, and that
都能保持高昂的兴致
they have a lot of different
并且在尝试不同事情的时候
moments where they can be
可以获得相应的奖励
And when they try something and
当他们在尝试时
they discover something for the
然后发现了新东西
first time, they definitely
他们肯定不会忘记
But if we throw up like a
如果我们将这些规则像
tooltip or some way of just
工具提示一样堆积到一起
making sure that we as the game
仅仅是为了
designers are comfortable
我们作为游戏开发者
knowing that they know
能确保玩家能知道规则
something, there's a pretty good
那玩家们之后有很大可能
chance that they'll forget it
会忘记这些规则
later on since they didn't go
因为他们自己并没有
through the process of learning
经历过学习的过程
So when I go into a game for the
当我刚开始玩一个游戏时
first time, I want to learn how
如果它发生在一个世界
to navigate the world, if it
那我希望能够尽快
takes place in a world, as
了解这个世界
quickly as possible or just how
或者尽快理解
to understand the rules of the
游戏规则
game as quickly as possible, but
但又不希望太快
not so quickly that I'm kind of
因为这样会
robbed of my curiosity to
剥夺我探索
explore them a little bit
游戏规则的好奇心
So I tend to get a sense for
所以我倾向于
what the game is, and if the
整体了解这个游戏
game continues to surprise me,
如果它能持续带来惊喜
I'll make it through to the
那我就会坚持到通关
&gt;&gt; Wow, that was learning the
这就是 Where Cards Fall 的
rules in Where Cards Fall, and
规则教学部分
that definitely feels a part of
它与整个游戏融合完美
the game's world, and I think
我想 大家都能
everyone can learn from what Sam
从 Sam 所说的主动发现中
said about active discovery.
学到东西
And this is not just for games.
主动发现不仅仅适用于游戏
Active discovery is so much
主动发现比
better than reading tooltips or
阅读工具提示
chasing a pointing arrow, and to
或者追着一个箭头跑要好的多
Sam's point, being told isn't as
Sam 认为
much fun or, frankly, effective
被告知不如自行发现
as discovering something for
来得更有趣 更有效
It's kind of like being told
这就像 有人和你说
about a vacation versus being on
他刚刚度过的假期
that vacation yourself.
和你自己去度假的差别
It's way more fun, and you're
亲自体验要有趣的多
if you actually go through that
用户记忆也会
experience.
更加深刻
So whether you're creating an
所以不管你是在设计一个
app or a game, aspire to be
App 还是游戏
stunning.
要力求出色
Create beautiful experiences,
创造美妙的体验
polish your visual design so it
完善你的视觉设计
looks and feels just a part of
让它看起来融入
your app or game's world.
你的 App 或游戏世界
Okay, timeless.
接下来是永不过时
This has been on my mind since
在我与音效设计师 Hugo 探讨后
talking with Hugo, a sound
我对这个词印象深刻
Most of you will recognize this.
你们肯定都听过这段铃声
[ Ringtone ]
[ 铃声 ]
I'm always looking for where
我听到这个总是
that phone is.
想找手机
But what reminded me of this
但让我想到这段铃声的
ringtone was this part of the
是这次访谈的一段
&gt;&gt; If we create a ringtone for
如果我们要为新的 iPhone
the new iPhone, then we don't
设计铃声
want it to sound dated after a
我们当然不希望一年后
year, of course.
它听起来就很过时
It should still be a great
它应该在五年后
ringtone after 5 years, and
听起来也是一个好的铃声
maybe people will still remember
甚至人们在十年后
it after 10 years.
还能想起它
&gt;&gt; It was actually this section
正是这一部分
of the quote that really made me
让我想到了
think of timelessness.
永不过时
You know, it makes sense for a
一个铃声不能听上去过时
ringtone not to want to sound
这很有道理
dated, but this could also apply
但永不过时同样也适用于
to your visual and interaction
你的视觉设计
design too.
和互动设计
Hugo used this word "durability"
在采访过程中
to describe quality during our
Hugo 使用“耐用性”来描述品质
interview, and I think that's
我觉得这个词
really great.
用到很好
If we all aspire to create
如果我们都能创造出
designs that are just a little
更加持久的设计
bit longer lasting, it not only
那不仅仅能
would save us time and effort
节省我们现在付出的时间与精力
now, but it would put us into
还能将我们带到一个
the right mindset to provide
正确的观念模式中
something that we create with
让我们有机会做出
the opportunity to be timeless.
永不过时的设计
This final aspiration really had
最后一个设计倾向
an impact on me, and it came
对我有很大的影响
from my colleague Doug when I
它来自我的同事 Doug
asked him, "What makes great app
我问他“什么是好的 App 体验”
&gt;&gt; When I think of, like, great
当我想到
app experiences and things that
好的 App 体验
kind of provide something unique
以及能够为用户提供
and valuable to users, I think a
独特且有价值的事物时
lot of it is the substantial
我想到的是它们对用户生活
kind of positive effect that it
所带来的持续的
has on the user's life.
积极的影响
&gt;&gt; Doug, you nailed it.
Doug 你说的没错
Yes, absolutely, apps should
App 应该为用户
provide something unique and
提供独特且有价值的事物
valuable, but, actually, it was
但实际上
this part, the positive effect,
产生积极的影响
that really resonated with me.
才是能让我产生共鸣的部分
It made me reassess the apps and
它让我重新审视了手机上的
games on my phone.
App 以及游戏
After this interview, I
在这次采访后
literally scrolled through all
我真的翻看了
of my apps, and I thought, which
我所有的 App 我在想
ones have a positive effect on
哪些是对我的生活有
my life?
积极影响的呢
You know, wouldn't it be great
如果生活能够有
if life just had a little more
更多积极的东西
positivity?
不是很好吗
So next time you design, strive
所以下次你在做设计时
for simplicity because real life
请努力做到简单
if where we need to be spending
因为真实生活才是我们需要
our energy.
关注的
Aspire to be stunning because we
力求出色因为我们需要从
all need a break from chaos, and
生活的忙乱中寻得休息的时间
it's really nice to escape and
如果能够体验一些美妙的事物
experience something beautiful.
就太好了
Design to be timeless.
让设计变得永不过时
Think about how your designs can
想想看如何让你的设计
be good now but also years from
不仅仅在当下是优秀的
now because we could all design
更能一直延续到许多年后
to be a little less trendy and
因此我们设计时应该少一些跟风
definitely more durable.
多一些耐用的考虑
And finally, think about how you
最后 想想如何
could have a positive impact on
能给人们的生活带来
people's lives.
积极的影响
And, you know, this can manifest
不同的 App
itself in really different ways
可以通过不同的方式
depending on your app.
展示出来
It could be maybe that
积极有可能
positivity is being really
指的是准确
accurate, or maybe it's just
也可能指的是
being super entertaining.
极富娱乐性
Maybe it's just making someone's
也可以是
life or day feel a little bit
让人们的生活更轻松
easier.
我希望你们能
these thoughts to be as
和我一样
inspiring as I did.
从中获得启发
I'm sure you're thinking now,
你们现在肯定在想
though, well, sure, this has
没错 今天所说的这些
been mildly inspiring and
都启发性的
somewhat educational, but what
很有教育意义
can I do?
但我能做什么呢？
What can I actually take away
我可以从中吸取什么
and apply to my work?
并应用到我的工作中呢
Well, I wanted to know that too.
其实我也想知道
After talking with so many
在与这么多
different people from different
不同背景的人交谈之后
backgrounds, I wanted to know
我想要知道他们
what they learned -- what they
学会了些什么
learned on the job through their
在工作过程中
experiences.
学到了些什么
So through a series of
所以 我又问了一系列问题
questions, I uncovered a few
我发现了这些设计师们
tips and techniques that these
在设计过程中
designers use regularly when
常用的一些小贴士和
designing.
小技巧
And something important to
但在开始介绍它们之前
mention about design before we
我们需要知道一件重要的事情
get started is, yes, design is
设计很难
hard because nobody sets out to
没有人想要设计一个
create a bad app.
不好的 App
Making great designs is what we
我们都想做出
all strive for, but let's be
好的设计
honest.
但说实话
We don't always achieve it, and
并不是每个人都能做到
that's okay because we keep
但是没关系 因为我们不断地在尝试
trying and we learn a lot along
也在尝试的过程中 学到了不少东西
Okay, let's go ahead and hear
好的 让我们首先来看
this first technique, and it
第一个小技巧
really surprised me.
这个技巧让我很惊讶
It came up when I was talking
它是字体设计师 Loic
with Loic [phonetic], a type
在和我交流时提出的
designer, and I asked him, "What
我问他“你有什么
helps you with your work?"
工作技巧”
&gt;&gt; So in the case of type
拿字体设计来说
design, for instance, we've
我们已经有
developed all kinds of little
各种各样的
drawing tricks.
绘画技巧
In type design especially,
而在字体设计中
subjectiveness I feel can
我认为主观性的影响
[inaudible] even more than in
比其它方面
other aspects of design because
要大得多
we go to the depth of how the
因为例如我们
particular curve of, on the
要深入研究小写 m 顶部弧度的大小
And we can have a 10-minute
而这个问题我们
discussion only on that.
能讨论十分钟
But the difficult part is
难就难在你
describing what you see in words
要如何用语言描述你所
that the other person is going
看到的东西 才能
to understand the way you mean
让其他人理解你的意思
it, and that's very difficult
特别是当你谈论的
when you're talking about shape.
是形状时
But one way we started doing
有一些同事的处理方式
that with some of my colleagues
是将我们看到的形状
was basically redrawing the
重新绘制
shape we're looking at with
把它们的特点
exaggerated features, where we
夸张的表达出来
basically kind of make a
就和我们
caricature of what we are
平时常看的漫画类似
So if I'm pushing what I'm
如果我将我所看到的
seeing to the extreme of why I
东西往我认为
find it ugly or uncomfortable,
丑陋或者不舒适的方向夸张
it's because it feels like that
那是因为它本身给我的
to me.
就是这种感觉
And through that drawing,
通过绘画
usually the other people can
用户通常会看到
start seeing that much more
经过低调处理的
toned down but existing feature
设计元素
of the design that they weren't
用户一开始
necessarily perceiving before
可能并不会注意这些
because that's not what they
因为这不是他们
were looking at.
会看到的
So it is about trying to make
所以你需要努力让
people see the world through
用户从你的角度
your eyes and the other way
来看这个世界
around, like gaining the ability
同时 你也需要拥有
to see the world through their
从用户的角度看世界的能力
eyes, so that you can then find
这样你就能发现
that third place that is
你们对世界的
actually the joint gaze that you
共同关注点
And that's the, that I think to
我认为找到这个
me is the key of a successful
关注点是
collaboration in design is
成功设计的关键
&gt;&gt; Wow. Before we even dig into
在我们进一步研究
this technique, have you thought
这个技巧之前 我想问一下
about type design?
你们有考虑过字体设计吗
I mean, every single letter that
我的意思是
you text, and email, and that
你发短信 发邮件 阅读的
you read, that's been designed,
每一个字母都是经过设计的
and type designers care so much
字体设计师们对细节
about detail that they've
高度关心
invented ways to communicate
他们发明了交流形状的方式
about shape when there are no
在无法语言描述时使用
That's just so cool.
真的是太酷了
So to Loic's point, when you're
Loic 认为
designing for others, it's
当你为用户设计时
really necessary to see the
你需要从他们的角度来看世界
world through their eyes, and
而这个小技巧
this technique helps achieve
就能帮我们做到
that.
将你的想法以夸张形式画出来
others to do the same.
让其他人也照做
It's really the importance of
从别人的角度考虑问题
putting yourself in others'
非常重要
shoes because you can better
因为这样可以更好地
understand their world.
理解他们的世界
And this is a great tool for
在无法用文字描述时
communication if words are not
这就是另外一种好的沟通方式
doing it, and it'll help you
它能帮你
understand what others are
理解别人眼中的事物
This next technique is going to
接下来我将通过一个故事
be unveiled through a story.
介绍下一个小技巧
Actually, even better, a first
这个故事是有关第一份工作的
job story.
这很有趣
Because you learn a lot on your
因为你可以从第一份工作中
first job, and they have a huge
学到很多东西 并产生巨大的影响
So I asked my colleague Doug
我问我的同事 Doug
what he learned at his first
从第一份设计工作中 学到了什么
&gt;&gt; One of the real kind of ahas
我觉得让我最受益匪浅的
for me was a question that I got
是一个问题
at the Tech Museum from the Head
我刚进 Tech Museum 时
of Design that was essentially,
设计总监问我
why is this good?
为什么这是个好东西
Why is this thing that you just
你刚刚给我的东西
gave me good?
好在哪里呢
And, you know, my initial
我的第一反应是
reaction was, well, because I
因为我觉得
think this will be easy for
这样子人们
people to do.
使用起来比较方便
And, you know, he responded,
总监反问我
like, well, how do you know
那你又怎么知道呢
that?
你是怎么知道这个
going to be easier than the way
方式比我们现在用的方式
that we do it now?
要简单呢
And I kind of realized that I
这时候 我才反应过来
didn't know the answer to that.
我并不知道这个问题的答案
And then, I realized what he was
这时 我才意识到
really asking is, should we put
他真正想问的是
all of this energy into making
你提议的改变是否
the changes that you're
值得我们付出这么多
suggesting?
努力呢
How can we be sure that that's
我如何确保这是
the right thing to do?
正确的事情呢
And to answer that question, I
为了回答这个问题
opened up -- it might have been
我打开了 大概是
Microsoft Paint [laughs] -- and
微软的画图[ 笑声 ]
I drew a picture, and I took it
然后我画了一幅画
out onto the museum floor, and
带到了博物馆一楼
basically asked visitors to give
我对屏幕上的东西
me their impression of what they
进行了不同的布局
thought they should do based on
并采访了访客们
kind of how I had arranged
对我的设计
things on the screen.
有什么看法
&gt;&gt; So what Doug was talking
Doug 想要表达
about here, and he went on to
想要解释的是
explain, that it was this method
正是这种制作原型的
of prototyping that helped him
方法帮助他
answer that question from his
回答了老板提出的
boss.
问题
Why should we put energy into
为什么我们要为你的想法投入
your idea?
精力呢
So what Doug learned at his
Doug 从他
first design job was that he
第一份设计工作中学到的是
could not assume that his
不能凭空认为他的设计
designs were going to work.
能够达到他想要的效果
And this actually also came up
在我与 Gary 之间的对话中
in my conversation with Gary.
他也提到了这一点
&gt;&gt; It wasn't just designed on
这不仅仅是简单的纸上设计
paper, implemented in code, and
代码编辑
sort of assumed that that was
然后就默认这个设计有效果
going to work.
你不能仅仅通过
own experience and through
你自己的经验以及与他人的交谈
chatting that something's going
就默认某种功能可以实现
to work.
你需要不断地走出去 不断尝试
&gt;&gt; And I think this is the part
我认为这一点
that's really important not to
十分重要 不能忽视
You know, in this case, we are
我们现在讨论的是
talking about trying designs in
在真实世界的实际场景中
context out in the real world to
测试你的设计
vet solutions to problems, and
找到解决问题的方法
trying solutions is something
而尝试解决方法
that Sam mentioned too.
也是 Sam 所提及的
&gt;&gt; One of our ethos's is to
我们的目标之一就是
solve a problem.
解决问题
Put it in front of players and
将它放到玩家面前
see how they react.
看他们的反应
See if they're learning what
看他们是否能学到
they need to learn.
应该学会的东西
And if we need to do more, we'll
如果没有达到效果 我们会做更多
It's impossible to rush the
想要匆忙之间完成
creative process of making a
游戏的创意设计是不可能的
game because so much of what's
因为你所能记得的
special about the games that you
游戏的特别之处
remember are decisions that seem
正是那些
very obvious and very small but
显而易见而又细微的决定
take a really, really long time
但它们却需要很长的时间
to arrive at.
才能做出
And you can't hire more people
雇佣更多的人也不能让
to get there faster.
速度加快
You just have to sit with it and
你能坐在你的位置上
continue working on it until the
不断地尝试
best solutions arise.
直到出现最佳方案
&gt;&gt; So Sam said something here
Sam 在这里提到了
that I want to expand on.
我想要补充的东西
More people are not going to fix
人多不一定能
a creative problem.
解决创造性的问题
Great artists are patient.
优秀的艺术家们都非常耐心
Sometimes you just get writer's
当你遇到了瓶颈时
block and there's no amount of
与任何人的任何对话
conversation that's going to fix
都不能帮你解决问题
it, so you have to wait and just
所以你能做的就是等着
let that creative process
让创造自行发生
And that's okay.
这样可以了
It's a part of the process, and
这是创造的一部分
sometimes that's exactly what is
有时候这也是高品质
needed to produce quality.
所需要的
So the theme really from these
所以最后三个音频的主题
last 3 clips is to go out and
就是要走出去
try your designs in context with
到现实生活的情景中
real people.
尝试你的设计
Show people prototypes and learn
让人们看到你的设计原型
from their feedback.
听取他们的反馈
This is a really essential
这个技巧十分重要
technique to help work through
它能为你在做出设计决定时
your design decisions.
提供帮助
So we can learn a lot from each
我们相互之间学到了许多东西
other, so I wanted to know what
因此我想知道设计师
advice would one designer give
会给另一个设计师
to another designer.
什么样的建议
&gt;&gt; Learn how to accept, and
学会去接受 分类
sort, and prioritize the
并按反馈的优先级排序
feedback as it comes in, whether
不管这些反馈是
it's from yourself or from
来自你自己还是别人
You will learn so much more
如果你抗拒这些反馈
quickly than if you are
那你不会学到很多东西
defensive and you just, like,
就会少了很多
buckle down.
就像被锁住一样
&gt;&gt; I personally struggle with
这对我来说有点难
I can almost not help becoming
当我听到有关
defensive when I hear feedback
我负责项目的反馈时
on a project I'm working on.
我会不自觉的抗拒
It's like this instinctual
这就是一种本能的反应
reaction, especially if I just
特别是如果我
spent late nights and weekends
为这个项目付出了无数个
working on something.
夜晚与周末
But still, I know it's
但我也知道乐于接纳意见
important, but I wanted to know
是十分重要的 但我想知道原因
Again, why is it important to be
我们来到了这个问题 乐于接纳意见为什么
open to feedback?
很重要呢
&gt;&gt; I think there's also just a
我认为事实是
reality, which is after you've
如果你使用了
used your own work for some
你自己的设计
amount of time, you naturally
一段时间后
develop some blind spots.
你自然会产生盲点
And that's where having a really
所以在设计过程中
great, collaborative team and
如果你身边能有
people that you trust around you
极具协作性的优秀团队
to help critique your work is a
或者你极其信任的人
really important part of the
对你的工作进行审视
design process.
是非常重要的
So you can get fresh eyes on
这样才能不断有新鲜的目光
stuff and trust that people have
和善意的人们
the good intentions and they're
为你提供好的建议
great insights of how you can
帮助你进行改进
&gt;&gt; Totally.
说真的
I've been there.
我有这样的经历
I've definitely been too close
我曾经过于投入项目
on a project and lost sight of a
以至于失去了
big picture or overlooked some
观剧观念 还忽视了一些细节
So by being open to feedback,
乐于接受反馈能方便
it's really easy then to have
你团队的成员
someone else like your team or
或者其他你寻求意见的人
somebody that you asked a
为你提出一些建议
question to give you something,
这些建议
some piece of information that
能够帮助你
can help you improve your
改进你的设计
And I really like that May-Li
May-Li 用了一个词 我很喜欢
said this word, "trust," to
那就是“信任”
trust the people around you.
信任你周围的人
So be open to feedback.
所以大胆去接受反馈吧
It makes everything better and
它能让所有事情变得更好
just ups the overall quality of
也能提升你设计的
design in your work.
整体品质
So this next technique is more
接下来将要讨论的与其说是技巧
of a mindset, and it came up
不如说是一种思维方式
when I asked Cas, who works on
它是平台设计师 Cas 提出的
platform patterns, "How do you
我问他“你是如何
approach designing for so many
为这么多人
people?"
设计东西的呢”
&gt;&gt; Knowing what you don't know,
从某种程度上说 就是要了解未知
What I mean is that if you're
我的意思是
looking at these things or if
如果你正在看一些东西
you're designing for these
或者如果你正在设计这些东西
things, obviously, you have
那很明显
ideas and ways of using a
你有自己的想法
certain device or an app in your
和使用设备或者 App 的方式
own way, in your own
按你自己的用法 在自己的环境中
environment, in your own habits,
以自己的习惯使用
and you might know a little bit
你可能也对你的朋友的
about how your friends are using
使用方法略有了解
it, or how you've seen other
或者你曾经看过其他人使用
people use it, or maybe feedback
或者获得过
you're getting, but it's a
一些反馈
really big world, and there's a
但这个世界很大
lot of people out there, and
有很多人
they all have their own needs,
他们有着自己的需求
their own habits, their own way
自己的习惯
of going through life.
自己的生活方式
And so you have to be very
所以你需要谨记
mindful that how you think about
你的思考方式
things or your opinions are not
或者你的观点
always, first of all, correct
并不永远都正确
ones, nor the only ones.
或者不是唯一的正解
&gt;&gt; I really like how Cas put
我很喜欢 Cas 一开头
this at the beginning -- know
所说的那句话
that you don't know.
“了解未知”
And he also used this word
在我与 Cas 的对话中
"modesty" through our
他还提到了一个词 “谦逊”
To be unassuming when you're
当你在为这么多人设计产品时
designing for so many people.
不要妄下结论
And that is a really great
这是你设计时
headspace to be in when you're
需要牢牢记住的
approaching design; to be modest
要做到谦逊
and to be mindful.
并且处处留心
So how do you help keep people's
那如何才能在设计时
experiences top of mind when
将用户体验放到
you're designing?
首位呢
&gt;&gt; So in many ways, I just have
在许多方面 我需要
to be skeptical and ask
保持怀疑
questions if the idea in front
并对创意提出疑问
of me, is that going to work for
比如说 这个方法
example?
是否适合坐在轮椅中的人呢
Is that going to work for
是否适合那些
someone that has never used this
从未使用过这个
app before?
App 的人呢
Is it going to work for someone
是否适合那些刚从 PC
coming from a PC to a Mac?
转到 Mac 的人呢
You just have to ask lots of
你需要问自己许多问题
questions, and it can just start
这些问题能推动人们
people thinking about, oh, yeah,
进行思考
did I care enough to consider
我是否已经
that aspect of it?
考虑充分了呢
&gt;&gt; Right. So this may seem
这听起来
really simple, but it's
似乎很简单
important to ask questions,
但问问题十分重要
especially from different
特别是从不同角度问问题
That's going to help you
这能帮助你在工作
maintain quality throughout your
的过程中保持产品的品质
work and keep those other
并将用户体验
people's experiences in mind.
记在心中
So design is a really
设计是一个
collaborative process, and
合作的过程
there's a lot that goes into
合作需要付出
making collaboration work.
许多努力
At one point or another, we're
我们终有一天会
all going to start on a new
开始一个新的项目 或者
project or a new team, so what
加入一个新的团队
helps make that process a little
那怎样才能让这个流程变得
bit easier?
容易一些呢
&gt;&gt; I always like to set
我喜欢一开始就
expectations upfront.
设定期望
I just say, hey, this is how I
我会告诉人们 嗨 我是这样的一个人
This is how I work.
这是我的工作方式
This is how I communicate.
这是我的沟通方式
How do you work?
你的工作方式是什么
How do you communicate?
你的交流方式呢
What's your preferred method of
你更喜欢通过什么方式来
communication?
沟通呢
And by the way, here's the goals
顺便提一下 我觉得
that I think we are working
这个是我们的共同目标
And here are the things that are
对我来说 这些事情
important to me.
很重要
And please share with me the
请和我分享对你来说
same for you.
重要的事情
And I'll always sort of say it
我通常都会用一种警告的
with a caveat like, "We're going
方式来表达
to get all this business out of
“我们需要解决这件事情
the way, and we're going to
在处理过程中
speak very directly about it."
我希望我们可以坦诚地讨论”
&gt;&gt; I know for me, talking about
对我而言
communication can be awkward,
讨论沟通方式有些尴尬
but after I tried this
但我试着使用这一技巧时
technique, I learned that it
我发现它能
helps avoid so much drama and
帮我避免许多麻烦以及误解
So talk about communication,
如果你正在团队中工作
especially if you're working on
别犹豫 好好讨论一下沟通的问题
Work towards the same goal about
一起为了同一目标
creating something great.
创造优秀的事物而努力
So really, these six techniques
真的 这六个技巧都与
are all about caring about the
关心他人
other people and having tools to
以及沟通工具有关
talk about it, and you have to
你必须关心别人
care about other people and put
把自己放在
yourself second.
次要的位置
Be mindful of their lives and be
处处留心他们的生活
modest about your own because we
并保持谦逊
just learned you can't assume.
因为你不能妄下定论
You have to go out and try your
你需要走出去
designs through prototyping and
使用原型法尝试你的设计
also really remain open to
同时还需乐于接受反馈
That's essential to making
这对改进你的
progress in design because, as
设计至关重要
May-Li said, we all develop
正如 May-Li 所说的
blind spots, and we're not only
我们都有自己的盲点
designing to make progress, but
我们不是为了取得进展而设计
we want to get closer to
但我们确实想更靠近
reaching our own aspirations and
我们的志向与目标
So these techniques are used by
这些技巧是
real designers that I talked to,
我所采访过的设计师们使用的
and they help them go through
这些技巧在他们设计时
the process of designing, and it
为他们提供了帮助
makes their days a little bit
也让他们的工作变得轻松了一些
easier, so I hope they can help
我希望它们也能帮到你们
So after all of these
在采访了这么多人后
interviews, I learned that
我了解到 品质
quality is the result of time,
是时间 精力
effort, and care.
以及关心的结果
It's considered, it's crafted,
品质需要经过深思熟虑 精心雕琢
and it means something different
它对不同人有着
to different people.
不同的含义
I also learned that quality
品质还影响着
impacts our every day, that your
我们的日常生活
intentions are truly felt.
你的初衷能被真正的感知到
High quality evokes trust, and
高品质是信任的基础
that's really important, as well
它十分重要
as it has to be earned.
是需要努力才能挣得的
It's also important to strive
力求简单 出色
for simplicity, to aspire to be
永不过时
stunning, and design to be
这三点也同样重要
Just think about how your app or
你需要考虑你的 App 或者
game can have a positive impact
游戏能对人们对生活
on people's lives.
带来怎样的积极影响
And finally, working towards
最后 要完成一个
quality is all about
高品质的产品
communication, collaboration,
需要沟通 合作
and understanding, especially
以及理解 特别是
understanding the people you are
对你的用户群体的理解
So really, quality is a
品质是一个原则
principle.
品质是精心打造的
something that you have to ask
你需要问你自己
yourself, what does quality mean
品质对你意味着
to you?
什么
And you need to know your
你需要清楚你自己对品质的理解
interpretation to go forward, to
才能继续进行设计
put in that hard work that meets
将它融入到你的辛勤付出中
your expectations and hits your
使之满足你的期望
aspirations because, at the end
并达到你的目标
of the day, you're not designing
因为你并不是在为你自己
for you.
做设计
You're designing for other
你是在为那些将要使用你的
people who are going to use your
App 或者游戏的人做设计
So make great designs for them.
那么请为他们提供好的设计吧
Now, there are two important
有关伟大设计的品质
statements on quality in great
有另外两个重要的声明
design that stand alone.
需要单独说说
These are going to play back to
这两段音频将会连着播放
back, and I hope each offers
我希望每个音频都能
something different that you can
让你今天收获
take away from today.
一些不同的东西
&gt;&gt; Sensing the human behind the
能够觉察到体验背后的人性
experience I think is really an
是伟大作品的标志
&gt;&gt; A great design is going to be
一个伟大的设计将会是
the product of tremendous amount
无数付出
of effort, and creativity, and
创意 技巧
skill, and [laughs] late nights.
以及 [ 笑声 ] 熬夜的成果
It's going to seem effortless,
但它需要看起来似乎轻而易举
and it should hopefully recede
并且人们往往会
in people's consciousness.
意识不到
And in a way, I think you're
从某种角度来说
very aware of an interface which
人们往往会记得
has been poorly designed, and
一些设计粗糙的界面
you're not at all aware of an
但却不记得那些
interface which has been well
设计完美的界面
&gt;&gt; So I talked to a lot of
我和很多人都交谈过
people, and I saved something
并且特意为了结尾保留了一些
special just for the end.
很特别的东西
Since I had the opportunity to
因为我有机会与
talk to so many different
许多不同的设计师对话
designers, I had to ask them onw
我问了他们
final question, and it's
最后一个问题
something that I've always
这是我最想问的
wanted, wondered myself: What
也最好奇的
are designers' favorite colors?
“设计师们喜欢的颜色是什么”
&gt;&gt; Oh, wow.
哇
&gt;&gt; My favorite color?
我最喜欢的的颜色
&gt;&gt; I have to say--
应该是
&gt;&gt; Is there such a thing?
有这种东西吗
I don't think so.
我觉得没有呀
&gt;&gt; I would have said glitter,
我想说闪光
but it's not a color.
但这不是一种颜色
&gt;&gt; One of the things that I
好啦 我是真的很喜欢
really love is Tahitian blue.
大溪地蓝
&gt;&gt; But colors to me are like
但颜色对我来说就像心情一样
moods, and I do not have the
我每天都有着
same mood every day.
不同的心情
I don't think I even have the
甚至 我每个小时
same mood every hour, so.
都有不同的心情
&gt;&gt; I really like white.
我挺喜欢白色的
Is it really a color?
白色算一种颜色吗
I think that's one of the
我想这是我喜欢它
reasons why I like it.
的原因之一
&gt;&gt; My favorite color has been
我最喜欢的颜色是
amber.
琥珀色
&gt;&gt; I mean, lately, it's been
我最近最喜欢的颜色
green for some reason.
是绿色
I don't know why.
我也不知道为什么
&gt;&gt; I got to go back on this
我要回到这个
answer.
问题上来
Oh, it's actually Pantone 347.
我最喜欢的是潘通 347 号色
&gt;&gt; My favorite color is blue.
我最喜欢的颜色是蓝色
&gt;&gt; Like a happy blue, and blue
那种快乐的蓝色
is, like, always such a color of
蓝色总是代表着责任
responsibility, which is, like,
这简直就是在说我
&gt;&gt; But I just think it's, like,
我喜欢
soft and friendly.
温和友善的颜色
And food that's pink tastes
粉红色的食物
good.
尝起来都比较美味
&gt;&gt; I'm going to go with red.
红色是我最喜欢的颜色
&gt;&gt; Throw out a hex value.
我看看调色板
I don't have a favorite color.
我没有最喜欢的颜色
Every color's great.
每个颜色都很棒
&gt;&gt; [laughs] All right, maybe
[ 笑声 ] 好吧 我只能
I'll just answer for this moment
说我现在最喜欢的颜色
&gt;&gt; I don't wear any green.
我不穿绿色的衣服
My car's not green.
我的车也不是绿色的
But I just like the idea of
但是我很喜欢绿色
&gt;&gt; And I can't pick one because
我没法挑出一种单独的颜色
I wouldn't be able to pick a
就好像我不能单独挑出
single musical note, so I'll use
一个单独的音符
all of them where it makes
我会用适合各个场景的颜色
&gt;&gt; I'll need to check the spec
我觉得我可能要去
on that, I think.
查一下具体信息
System blue, of course.
当然是系统蓝啦
Yeah.
好的
&gt;&gt; Special thanks to everyone
特别感谢参与采访的
interviews.
每一个人
Thank you all so much.
谢谢大家
Have a great WWDC.
尽情享受你们的 WWDC 吧